Guide to UE Court Case Records, 1935-2000 UE.9.4
ULS Archives & Special Collections
UE Court Case Records
1935-2000
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. Legal Department
UE.9.4
323.75 Linear Feet (259 boxes)
The Legal department for the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) was responsible for maintaining records regarding legal suits concerning the union. This subgroup contains legal documents, as well as correspondence and printed materials, regarding arbitration, grievance, and other legal cases of UE locals and the national union.
Scope and Content Notes
The Legal department for the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) was responsible for maintaining records regarding legal suits concerning the union. This extremely large subgroup contains the records of any UE court case that did not concern the National Labor Relations Board. Materials include legal documents, as well as correspondence and printed materials, regarding arbitration, grievances, and other legal cases between companies and UE locals or the national union. A majority of the cases represent arbitrations or conflicts with Westinghouse or GE. Documents regarding the cases of individual UE members are also present.
Arrangement
This collection has been loosely arranged by subject, such as General Electric, Westinghouse, and other companies.
Access Restrictions
Records of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America are closed for a period of twenty-five years after their creation.
Acquisition Information
Gift of United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America in 1986, 1997, and 2002.
Previous Citation
UE Court Case Records, 1935-2000, UE.9.4, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
UE National Labor Relations Board Case Records, 1936-1990s, UE.9.2, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Correspondence; Unfair labor practices -- United States; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- United States -- History; General Electric Company; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. Legal Department; Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America -- History
- GE Arbitration, 1940s (Box 1)
- GE Arbitration, 1960s (Box 2)
- GE Grievances, 1985-1986 (Box 3-4)
- GE vs. Siaskiewicz Trial Materials (Box 5)
- GE Sacari Case (Box 6)
- GE Court Cases (Box 7)
- GE Arbitration (Box 8)
- GE Court Cases, 1940s (Box 9)
- GE Sacari Case (Box 10)
- GE Arbitration (Box 11)
- GE Court Cases (Box 12-13)
- GE Court Cases, 1950s-1960s (Box 14)
- GE Legal Cases (Box 15)
- GE Legal Cases, 1935, 1950s (Box 16)
- GE Court Cases, 1940s-1950s (Box 17)
- GE Court Cases (Box 18)
- GE Legal Transcripts (Box 19)
- GE Arbitration Transcripts (Box 20)
- GE Grievances, 1970s (Box 21-22)
- GE 3rd Step Grievances, 1960s-1980s (Box 23)
- GE Grievances, 1960s-1970s (Box 24)
- GE Grievances and National Dockets, 1980s (Box 25-27)
- GE Legal Cases (Box 28-29)
- GE Court Cases, 1970s-1980s (Box 30-39)
- GE Patternmakers Cases (Box 40)
- GE Grievances (Box 41-54)
- Steve Nelson and UE Legal Case against GE (Box 55-57)
- GM and Westinghouse Court Cases (Box 58)
- Westinghouse Legal Cases (Box 59-65)
- Walker v. Westinghouse (Box 66-67)
- Westinghouse Grievances, 1960s (Box 68-69)
- Westinghouse Legal Cases (Box 70)
- Westinghouse National Grievances, 1970s (Box 71)
- Westinghouse Grievances (Box 72-74)
- Westinghouse Equal Employment Opportunity Committee Arbitrations (Box 75)
- WABCO Grievances (Box 76-77)
- Westinghouse National Grievances (Box 78-87)
- Westinghouse Grievances, 1960-1961 (Box 88)
- Sylvania National Grievances (Box 89-90)
- Sylvania Court Cases (Box 91)
- Sylvania Arbitrations, 1954-1956 (Box 92)
- Harowe Servo Court Cases (Box 93-95)
- Harowe Servo and Western Electric Court Cases (Box 96)
- UE v. ITT, 1950s (Box 97-98)
- Reid Plastics Legal Files, 1991 (Box 100)
- Chamberlain Manufacturing Court Cases (Box 101)
- UE Contempt Cases (Box 102)
- Cases against Leo Jandreau (Box 103)
- Albert Fitzgerald v. James Carey (Box 104)
- District 4, 6, and 7 Legal Cases (Box 105-106)
- Court Cases #10-1275 (Box 107-137)
- Company Legal Cases, 1940s-1980s (Box 138-153)
- Closed Legal Files (Box 154-166)
- Legal Cases (Box 167-173)
- Legal Cases, 1940s (Box 174-175)
- Legal Cases, 1989-2000 (Box 176-226)
- Court Cases (Box 227-229)
- Legal Cases and Briefs (Box 230-236)
- Legal Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 237-239)
- Grievances (Box 240-242)
- Legal Cases (Box 243-246)
- Legal Department (Box 247-252)
- Legal Files, 1980s (Box 253)
- Correspondence and Cards regarding Grievances, 1940s-1970s (Box 254)
- Legal Transcripts (Box 255)
- National Arbitrations, 1970 (Box 256)
- GE 3rd Step Grievances (Box 257-258)
- Local 612 Cases (Box 259)